JOÃO NORIM BANDEIRA Curriculum Vitae

+351 911 099 213 | joaonorimbandeira@gmail.com Gondomar, Porto, Portugal https://norim13.github.io

Education

2012-2017

Integrated Master's in Informatics and Computing Engineering

Faculdade de Engenharia da Universidade do Porto

Grade: 17/20

Relevant courses: Databases, Software Engineering, Web Development, Mobile Development, Object Oriented Programming, Computer Graphics, Computer Networks, Software Architecture, Agile Methodologies, Datamining and Machine Learning, Software Testing

Experience

April 2017 - Current

Research Grant - Use of BLE Beacons in a mobile ticketing solution for public transportation

Faculdade de Engenharia da Universidade do Porto

September 2015 - February 2016

Teaching Assistance in a Computer Graphics course Faculdade de Engenharia da Universidade do Porto

Skills

Languages: Portuguese (native), English (fluent)

Software development: Web Development, Mobile Development, Databases, Testing

Projects

2016 Visitas guiadas Casa da Música | Grade: 18/20

Functioning mobile app prototype to guide tours in Casa da Música, including 3D models and panoramic views of the concert halls and other rooms. **Technologies:** Ionic Framework, Three.js, Ruby on Rails (web-based back office), PostgreSQL.

2016 **ACME Café** | Grade: 18/20

Cafeteria order management platform. Mobile application for users to make their orders (access to menu, vouchers and order history). Another mobile application to receive the users' orders, and pass them to the employees. Back end with a REST API to receive data from the apps and store it in the cloud. **Technologies:** Android, Node.js, PostgreSQL.

2016 **EZTrip** | Grade: 18/20

Mobile app for trip planning by public transportations in Porto city. **Technologies:** Ionic

Framework, eXistdb (XML database).

2015 **Rios+** | Grade: 19/20

Web and mobile apps to provide experts in rivers and the general population with several ways to submit data about the state/health of the rivers. **Technologies:** Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Java (Android), GeoServer, PostgreSQL.

2014 **Venn** | Grade: 19/20

Social network where users can share text, photo or video posts with their circles of

friends. Post can be scheduled, and an expiration date can be set.

Technologies: Smarty, PHP, Javascript, PostgreSQL.

About

I'm a 22 years software developer from Porto, and just finished the Integrated Master in Informatics and Computing Engineering at FEUP. I have no problem working with new or unfamiliar technologies, I'm open to new ideas and experiences, and consider myself a quick learner, and always eager to learn new technologies.

During my academic path, I've worked in many different areas, with special focus on such as web and mobile development, but also with databases management, or QA & Testing, among others. I am also very familiar with software development practices and Agile methodologies.

Besides software development, my hobbies are photography, karate, which I practice since 2001, currently with *shodan* graduation (1st Dan), and I also play the guitar.